

Jyoti Gupta

Software Developer

Gurgaon, India +919799931871 · jyotigupta13997@gmail.com

Skills

Html & CSS

Bootstrap

C#

.Net Framework

ASP .NET MVC

ASP .NET Core

SQL Server

Python

Kendo UI

ASP .NET Web API

Azure AD

Entity Framework

Profile

Having near 5.7 years of experience working with web applications in Asp.Net

MVC and Web APIs. Experienced in database works, LINQ. Good communication skills and adaptable to environment, efficient in taking workloads, managing works on priority manner.

Employment History

Lead Engineer - Development, FIS Global Business Solutions India Pvt. Ltd, Gurgaon

October 2021 — Present

- My role here is to do the development along with documenting work processes, create code optimizations and also handling database and UI stuff.
- Achieved better UI, helped in achieving project goals before time, provided on time support to teams

Software Developer, RSK Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon July 2019 — October 2021

- The role is to do both fronted and back-end development, helping in designing process, giving ideas for project architecture, following agile methodologies
- Involved in improving work process, provided multiple project support and on time goals achievement

Associate Application Developer, Success Ladder Technologies, Alwar May 2018 — July 2019

 My role here is to create web designs and then make them dynamic, as well as handling .net projects along with some part of app designs using Xamarin

Subject Matter Expert, Chegg India

January 2018 — May 2018

Key Project Experiences

FIS Scanner Web APIs

Technology: - .Net Core 6.0, SQL Server, MySQL, .Net Core Web API, RabbitMQ

Libraries:- CLI Wrap

OS:- Windows, Linux

Scanner Tool:- Nuclei

Tools: - Visual Studio 2022

Detail: - These APIs are built in two parts, one that runs over windows box and the other over Linux box where it actually runs nuclei scanner which takes on custom templates created through API and run the scans for the target sites and gets back to results to store on MySQL and the UI display is on ServiceNow.

Advanced Vulnerability Analysis (AVA)

Technology: - Asp.Net MVC, .Net Framework 4.7, SQL Server, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery, Kendo UI, Telerik Reporting

Tools: - Visual Studio 2019, SSMS

Detail: - The tool is built to create Pentest Program Management for security or pen testers team to manage their analysis, as of creating engagement, adding their findings, upload Ips so on.

Black Duck Console App

Technology: - C#, SQL Server, Black Duck Scanner App

API Used: - Black Duck Scanner API

Tools: - Visual Studio 2019/2022, Postman, SSMS

Details: - The work of this console app to fetch scans, projects, releases and vulnerability data from the API and store them into SQL tables to be pushed into ServiceNow (SNOW

MACOM UK

Technology: - Asp.Net MVC, .Net Framework 4.7, SQL Server, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery

Autodesk Forge

Technology: - Asp .Net Core, JavaScript, HTML, SQL Server

Logistics UK

Technology: - Asp .Net Core, jQuery, HTML, Bootstrap, SQL Server, Microsoft Dynamics 365

Education

B.Tech, Modern Institute of Technology and Research Centre, Alwar

March 2014 — April 2018

Graduated in Computer Science and Engineering

12th, Central Public Sr. Sec. School, Alwar

Courses

Cyber Fundamental & Pragmatics, IIT Delhi

Achievements

Python Certified Entry Level Programmer (PCEP)
April 2023

OpenEDG Certification Verification Service (OCVS) test